housingwire.com 2017-10-10

# Privacy Policy

_Last Updated on February 1, 2015_

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for HousingWire Magazine and HousingWire.com, the HW Knowledge Center and other applications (collectively referred to as “HW Services”), and to any services that display this notice. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to "HousingWire" include HousingWire.com and HousingWire Magazine.

The HW Services may contain links to other websites for your convenience and information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites.

This Privacy Policy, covers the following:

  * What information do we gather about you?
  * What do we do with the information we gather about you?
  * With whom do we share the information that we gather?
  * What is our email policy?
  * How do I change or update my personal information?
  * How do I opt-out from receiving emails?
  * Is my information protected?
  * Compliance With Legal Process
  * Children's Guidelines
  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Changes to This Privacy Policy

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**

The information gathered when you interact with the HW Services falls into two categories: 1) Personal information, which includes personal information you supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, register for one of our sites, enter a contest or provide your email address and 2) Non-personal information collected through technology, which includes tracking information collected by us as well as third parties.

**_Personal Information That You Give Us_**

**Registration Information**

Registration for the HW Services may require that you supply certain personal information, including a unique email address and demographic information (company name, job title, phone number and job function) to register.

**Billing and Credit Card Information**

To enable payment and donations via the HW Services, we collect and store name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card information and other billing information. This information will only be shared with third parties who help to complete the purchase transaction. Examples of this include fulfilling orders and processing credit card payments.

**User Generated Content and Public Activities**

We offer you opportunities to engage in public activities on HousingWire.com. "Public activities" are any actions you take on HousingWire.com that are designed to be visible to other users, including comments, recommendations, reader reviews, ratings or any other items that you submit. Any information you disclose in your public activities, along with your screen name or ID, or any image or photo, becomes public and may be used by HousingWire for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you choose to engage in public activities, you should be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, collected and used by other users of these areas. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in the course of your public activities and we have no responsibility to publish, take down, remove or edit any of your public activities or submissions. For more information, read the Forums, Discussions and User Generated Content section of the Terms of Service.

If you have registered for a HousingWire.com account, we will track and aggregate your public activities on HousingWire.com. By choosing to participate in public activities, you are electing to share and display such public activities via HousingWire.com. Also, public activities may be included in RSS feeds, APIs and made available to other websites via other formats. As a result, your public activities may appear on other websites, blogs, or feeds. Keep in mind that we are not responsible for any personal information you choose to make public via your public activities, and you agree that such sharing will be deemed to have been done by you, not HousingWire. When you share or recommend links to content on a third-party platform (such as Facebook, Google+ and Twitter), that action and any information you share will be covered by their privacy policy.

**Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers**

HousingWire collects personal information from you when you participate in sweepstakes, contests or special offers. If this information is also being collected by a third party other than HousingWire, we will notify you at the same time. If you do not want any personal information shared, you should not participate in the sweepstakes, contest or special offer.

**Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research**

HousingWire may collect personal information from you in connection with voluntary surveys conducted via the HW Services. Data may be collected through the HW Services, on the phone or through the mail. The information you provide may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection.

**Conferences and Live Events**

We often receive information about attendees to our live events from sign-in and registration lists. We may share this information with event or promotion sponsors, in which case we will notify you when we collect the information.

**_Non-Personal Information Collected Using Technology_**

**Information Collected by Us Using Technology**

We use various Internet technologies to manage the HW Services and track use of the Services. Non-personal information that we collect using these technologies may be combined with other information about you.

**Device Information.**  We may collect non-personal information about the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access the HW Services, such as IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language and other transactional information.

**Cookies, Beacons, Local Storage and Other Similar Technologies.**  We use "cookies," Web beacons, HTML5 local storage and other similar technologies. These technologies allow us to manage access to and use of the Services and help us understand how people use the HW Services. You may not be able to access certain areas of our websites, including HousingWire.com, if your computer does not accept cookies from us.

**Do Not Track Signals.   **We do not respond to browser-based "do not track" signals.  The HW Services may transmit non-personally identifiable website usage information about our visitors to a reputable third party in order to show you advertising for HousingWire when you visit other sites. For more information about our third-party ad server, or to learn your choices about not having this non-personal information used to target ads to you, please [click here](http://www.appnexus.com/platform-policy).

**Analytics Technologies.**  We have hired third parties to provide us information, reports and analysis about the usage, browsing patterns of users of the HW Services.

  * Google Analytics tracks and analyzes non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers on HousingWire.com. All data collected by Google Analytics on our behalf is owned and used by us. For more information about how Google Analytics collects data, please read their privacy policy at <http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>
  * Act-On Software tracks and analyzes anonymous usage and browsing patterns of our website users. All data collected by Act-On Software on our behalf is owned and used by HousingWire alone. For more information about Act-On Software’s privacy policy, go to <https://www.act-on.com/privacy-policy>

**IP Addresses.**  We may log your IP address (the location of your computer or device on the Internet). We use IP addresses for system administration and troubleshooting purposes, and to track access and use of the HW Services.

**Log Files and Your Reading History.  **We automatically log certain usage information about your use of HW Service, including a reading history of the pages you view. We use this information to understand usage patterns for the HW Service.

**Information Collected by Third Parties**

Some of the services and advertisements included in the HW Services are delivered or served by third-party companies. These companies may place or recognize cookies, Web beacons or other technology to track certain non-personal information about our website users. For example, in the course of serving certain advertisements, an advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser in order to collect certain information about your use of the HW Services. In many cases, this information could be used to show you ads on other websites based on your interests.

We do not have access to, nor control over, advertisers' or service providers' use of cookies or other tracking technologies or how they may be used.

You have choices about the collection of information by third parties on our website:

1) If you would like more information about advertisers' use of cookies, and about your option not to accept these cookies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).

2) If you would like to opt-out of having interest-based information collected during your visits to this or other sites, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Your access to our websites should not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**

**Provide the Services You Request**

We use the information we gather about you to enable your use of the HW Services, fulfill your requests for certain products and services, such as sending out electronic newsletters and enabling you to participate in and renew paid services, polls, contests, and message boards.

**Statistical Analysis**

We perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of users of the HW Services, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our subscriber base. We use this information for analysis purposes, including analysis to improve customer relationships.

**Customizing Your Experience**

We use the information that we collect to allow advertising to be targeted to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. We also use this information to customize certain features of the HW Services to provide you with an enhanced experienced based on the type of device you are using to access the HW Services, and in certain cases, provide you with requested services.

**Relevant Advertising**

We may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising on the HW Service to be targeted to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer's experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We disclose information to third parties only in aggregate or de-identified form.

**Email Newsletters**

HousingWire will periodically send you email newsletters or promotional email about services offered by HousingWire and its advertisers. For details about HousingWire email, please see the section labeled "What Is Our Email Policy?"

**WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION THAT WE GATHER?**

**Within HousingWire**

If you have registered to use the HW Services, we will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address or any information that personally identifies you without your permission.

We  share information about our audience in aggregate or de-identified form. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to restrict our use of aggregated or de-identified information in any way.

In the future, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, we may include your information among the transferred assets.

**Third Parties**

If you are a subscriber to HousingWire Magazine and subscribed either by mail, phone or online, we may exchange or rent your name and mailing address and certain other information, such as when you first subscribed to HousingWire Magazine (but not your email address) with other reputable companies that offer marketing information or products through direct mail.

If you prefer that we do not share this information, you may opt-out by emailing us at [custserv@housingwire.com](mailto:custserv@housingwire.com), or write to us at HW Customer Care, 1320 Greenway Drive Ste 870, Irving TX 75038.  If you are a current subscriber, please remember to include your account number and phone number in the body of your email or letter, and if you choose to opt-out via email, please include "Opt-out" in the subject line.

We may share information about attendees to our live events with sponsors or other third parties. If so, we will notify you when you provide us the information.

**Service Providers**

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, ad serving, shipping, email distribution, list processing and analytics or promotions management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for HousingWire, and they may not share, resell or use the data for their own direct marketing purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose your opt-out information to third parties so they can suppress your name from future solicitations, in accordance with applicable laws. We may occasionally release personal information as required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena. (For more information, see the "Compliance with legal process" section of this policy.)

**WHAT IS OUR EMAIL POLICY?**

**HousingWire complies with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003.**  We will not send you marketing messages if you have opted out. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address for commercial purposes without your permission. If you feel you have received an email from us in error, please contact [custserv@housingwire.com](mailto:custserv@housingwire.com).

**Account and Service-Related Email.**  HousingWire reserves the right to send you email relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit-card problems, other transactional emails and notifications about major changes to the HW Services and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive email specific to your participation in those activities.

**Email Newsletters.**  HousingWire offers several email newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter. To manage your newsletter preferences, you can login to your HousingWire.com account.

**Promotional Email.**  HousingWire may periodically email you messages about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each email.

**Survey Email.**  We may send you an email inviting you to participate in user surveys, asking for feedback on HousingWire.com and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve the HW Services, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.

**HTML Email.**  When you sign up to receive email from us, you can select either plain text or HTML (with images) format. If you select the HTML format, we may place a one-pixel gif to determine whether or not readers viewed the email. This process does not leave any information on your computer, nor does it collect information from your computer. HousingWire may share this data with others in aggregate only.

**Emails From You.**  If you send us emails, you should be aware that information disclosed in emails may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in emails. We will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

**Email This Article Feature.**  HousingWire.com readers may use this feature to email links to articles (or other content such as slideshows). The email addresses that you supply to this service are saved for your convenience for future articles you may wish to email; these addresses are not used for any other purpose, and will not be shared with any third parties.

**HOW DO I CHANGE OR UPDATE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

**Manage Your HousingWire.com Account in the My Account Area.**  You may review and update your HousingWire.com membership or account information and access your transaction history in the My Account area.

There are a number of things you can do in the My Account area to ensure your personal information is accurate and up to date. For one, you can update the information you provided during the free registration process. To gain access to the areas of the My Account area containing personal information, you will be asked to re-enter your password. If you do not remember your password, you can reset your password. If you need further assistance, please contact Customer Service.

**HOW DO I OPT-OUT FROM RECEIVING EMAILS?**

**Email Promotions**

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive email marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email.

If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [custserv@housingwire.com](mailto:custserv@housingwire.com) and provide your email address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe.

**Mail or Telephone Promotions**

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive mail or telephone solicitations originated by HousingWire, or if you prefer that we do not share this information with third parties for marketing purposes, please email us at [custserv@housingwire.com](mailto:custserv@housingwire.com) or write to us at HW Customer Care, 1320 Greenway Drive Ste 870, Irving TX 75038. If you are a current subscriber, please remember to include your account number and phone number in the body of your email or letter, and if you choose to opt-out via email, please put "Opt-out" in the subject line.

**IS MY INFORMATION PROTECTED?**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, technical and administrative controls to protect the information. Please note that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

**OTHER INFORMATION**

**Compliance With Legal Process**

We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the HW Services; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

**Children's Guidelines** / **COPPA Compliance  
**HousingWire does not knowingly collect or store any personal information about children under the age of 13.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

Under the California “Shine The Light” law, California residents may opt-out of HousingWire’s disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. As detailed above, you may choose to opt-out of the sharing of your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes at any time by submitting a request in writing to HW Customer Care, 1320 Greenway Drive Ste 870, Irving TX 75038 or by emailing us at [custserv@housingwire.com](mailto:custserv@housingwire.com). It is important to note that this opt-out does not prohibit disclosures made for non-marketing purposes.

**Changes to This Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use your personal information, the change will be posted on this page thirty (30) days prior to taking effect and registered users will be notified via email.
